export default {
  id: 'mid_4b',
  name: '상용한자(중학4/한자찾기)',
  data: [
    { question: '독:さら、ふ(ける)、ふ(かす)/음:こう', answer: ['更'] },
    { question: '독:곧을/음:こう', answer: ['梗'] },
    { question: '독:かた(い)/음:こう', answer: ['硬'] },
    { question: '독:골풀/음:しん', answer: ['芯'] },
    { question: '독:물흐를, 분비할/음:ひつ、ひ', answer: ['泌'] },
    { question: '독:꿀/음:みつ', answer: ['蜜'] },
    { question: '독:うた/음:', answer: ['唄'] },
    { question: '독:みつ(ぐ)/음:こう、く', answer: ['貢'] },
    { question: '독:くさり/음:さ', answer: ['鎖'] },
    { question: '독:뇌물/음:ろ', answer: ['賂'] },
    { question: '독:たま(わる)/음:し', answer: ['賜'] },
    { question: '독:まかな(う)/음:わい', answer: ['賄'] },
    { question: '독:つらぬ(く)/음:かん', answer: ['貫'] },
    { question: '독:つぶ(す)、つぶ(れる)/음:かい', answer: ['潰'] },
    { question: '독:か(つ)/음:', answer: ['且'] },
    { question: '독:세금/음:そ', answer: ['租'] },
    { question: '독:あら(い)/음:そ', answer: ['粗'] },
    { question: '독:はば(む)/음:そ', answer: ['阻'] },
    { question: '독:ねら(う)/음:そ', answer: ['狙'] },
    { question: '독:よろ(しい)/음:ぎ', answer: ['宜'] },
    { question: '독:두려워할/음:ぐ', answer: ['惧'] },
    { question: '독:운치/음:いん', answer: ['韻'] },
    { question: '독:ころ/음:', answer: ['頃'] },
    { question: '독:かたむ(く)、かたむ(ける)/음:けい', answer: ['傾'] },
    { question: '독:わずら(う)、わずら(わす)/음:はん、[ぼん]', answer: ['煩'] },
    { question: '독:반드시, 수염/음:す', answer: ['須'] },
    { question: '독:목/음:こう', answer: ['項'] },
    { question: '독:완고할/음:がん', answer: ['頑'] },
    { question: '독:나눌/음:はん', answer: ['頒'] },
    { question: '독:적을, 과부/음:か', answer: ['寡'] },
    { question: '독:진칠/음:じん', answer: ['陣'] },
    { question: '독:바퀴자국/음:き', answer: ['軌'] },
    { question: '독:やわ(らか)、やわ(らかい)/음:なん', answer: ['軟'] },
    { question: '독:かがや(く)/음:き', answer: ['輝'] },
    { question: '독:ぬぐ(む)/음:けい、え', answer: ['恵'] },
    { question: '독:ほ/음:すい', answer: ['穂'] },
    { question: '독:こお(る)、こご(える)/음:とう', answer: ['凍'] },
    { question: '독:むね、[むな]/음:とう', answer: ['棟'] },
    { question: '독:단련할/음:れん', answer: ['錬'] },
    { question: '독:베풀, 묵을/음:ちん', answer: ['陳'] },
    { question: '독:さ(す)、さ(さる)/음:し', answer: ['刺'] },
    { question: '독:난간, 테두리/음:らん', answer: ['欄'] },
    { question: '독:うと(い)、うと(む)/음:そ', answer: ['疎'] },
    { question: '독:매울/음:らつ', answer: ['辣'] },
    { question: '독:칙서/음:ちょく', answer: ['勅'] },
    { question: '독:たの(む)、たの(もしい)、たよ(る)/음:らい', answer: ['頼'] },
    { question: '독:せ/음:', answer: ['瀬'] },
    { question: '독:おそ(れる)、かしこ(まる)/음:い', answer: ['畏'] },
    { question: '독:진/음:るい', answer: ['塁'] },
    { question: '독:たた(む)、たた(み)/음:じょう', answer: ['畳'] },
    { question: '독:う(める)、う(まる)、う(もれる)/음:まい', answer: ['埋'] },
    { question: '독:리/음:りん', answer: ['厘'] },
    { question: '독:あこが(れる)/음:しょう、[どう]', answer: ['憧'] },
    { question: '독:ひとみ/음:どう', answer: ['瞳'] },
    { question: '독:かね/음:しょう', answer: ['鐘'] },
    { question: '독:かて/음:りょう、[ろう]', answer: ['糧'] },
    { question: '독:갑옷, 첫째/음:こう、かん', answer: ['甲'] },
    { question: '독:みさき/음:', answer: ['岬'] },
    { question: '독:お(す)、お(さえる)/음:おう', answer: ['押'] },
    { question: '독:いや(しい)、いや(しむ)、いや(しめる)/음:ひ', answer: ['卑'] },
    { question: '독:비석/음:ひ', answer: ['碑'] },
    { question: '독:そで/음:しゅう', answer: ['袖'] },
    { question: '독:뽑을/음:ちゅう', answer: ['抽'] },
    { question: '독:굴대/음:じく', answer: ['軸'] },
    { question: '독:の(びる)、の(ばす)、の(べる)/음:しん', answer: ['伸'] },
    { question: '독:띠/음:しん', answer: ['紳'] },
    { question: '독:おれ/음:', answer: ['俺'] },
    { question: '독:과자/음:か', answer: ['菓'] },
    { question: '독:はだか/음:ら', answer: ['裸'] },
    { question: '독:무리/음:い', answer: ['彙'] },
    { question: '독:고요할/음:ぜん', answer: ['禅'] },
    { question: '독:ひ(く)、はず(む)、たま/음:だん', answer: ['弾'] },
    { question: '독:はば/음:ふく', answer: ['幅'] },
    { question: '독:なえ、[なわ]/음:びょう', answer: ['苗'] },
    { question: '독:えが(く)、か(く)/음:びょう', answer: ['描'] },
    { question: '독:ねこ/음:びょう', answer: ['猫'] },
    { question: '독:うね/음:', answer: ['畝'] },
    { question: '독:おに/음:き', answer: ['鬼'] },
    { question: '독:かたまり/음:かい', answer: ['塊'] },
    { question: '독:みにく(い)/음:しゅう', answer: ['醜'] },
    { question: '독:たましい/음:こん', answer: ['魂'] },
    { question: '독:여러, 자주/음:るい', answer: ['累'] },
    { question: '독:찾을, 쓸쓸할/음:さく', answer: ['索'] },
    { question: '독:さかずき/음:はい', answer: ['杯'] },
    { question: '독:すぎ/음:', answer: ['杉'] },
    { question: '독:とこ、ゆか/음:しょう', answer: ['床'] },
    { question: '독:없앨/음:まつ', answer: ['抹'] },
    { question: '독:어두울/음:まい', answer: ['昧'] },
    { question: '독:매혹할/음:み', answer: ['魅'] },
    { question: '독:천천히할/음:じょ', answer: ['徐'] },
    { question: '독:ぬ(る)/음:と', answer: ['塗'] },
    { question: '독:길/음:と', answer: ['途'] },
    { question: '독:밀가루/음:めん', answer: ['麺'] },
    { question: '독:골짜기/음:きょう', answer: ['峡'] },
    { question: '독:はさ(む)、はさ(まる)/음:きょう', answer: ['挟'] },
    { question: '독:せま(い)、せば(める)、せば(まる)/음:きょう', answer: ['狭'] },
    { question: '독:ほお/음:', answer: ['頬'] },
    { question: '독:화분, 바리때/음:はち、[はつ]', answer: ['鉢'] }
  ]
}
